《行尸走肉》
我擦
Holy shit.
你还好吧
You all right?
还好
Yeah.
赫谢尔  你呢
Hershel?
咱们回去吧
Let's head back.
有车  有车
Car. Car.
趴下
Get down.
-戴夫  托尼  他们是说在这儿吗  -是的
- Dave? Tony? They said over here? - Yeah.
-伙计 告诉你 我听到枪声了 -我看到行尸了
- I'm telling you, man, I heard shots. - I saw roamers
-大概离这里两条街远  也许这附近还有更多  -情况紧急
- two streets over. Might be more around - It's hot.here.
-咱得马上离开这儿  -戴夫  托尼
- We gotta get out of here. - Dave! Tony!
闭嘴  白痴  你想把它们都吸引过来吗
Shut up, you idiot!  You wanna attract 'em?
跟紧点  我们会找到他们的
Just stick close. We're gonna find 'em.
老兄  他说了要跟紧的
Dude, he said to stay close.
托尼
Tony.
妈的
Shit!
不
No!
这会儿他们应该回来了
They should've been back by now.
他们只是被迫藏在某处
Yeah. They just got holed up somewhere.
咱明天一早就出发吧
We'll... we'll head out first thing in the morning.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
-给你  -谢谢
- Man. - Thanks.
卡尔  别沮丧  好吗
Carl, I want you to keep your head up, okay?
你老爸  他是最坚强的...
Your old man, he's the toughest son of a...
别在屋子里爆粗口
No cussing in the house.
抱歉
Sorry.
-洛莉  吃饭了  -她不在屋里
- Lori, dinner. - She's not in there.
她去哪了
Where is she?
卡尔  你上次见到你妈妈是在什么时候
Carl, when's the last time you saw your mom?
-今天下午  -她担心瑞克
- This afternoon. - She was worried about Rick,
并且让我帮忙看着卡尔
asked me to look in on Carl.
-她跟着他去了吗  -她没说
- She went after them? - She didn't say that.
大家别慌  应该就在这附近的
Nobody panic. Gonna be around here somewhere.
-它们为啥不离开  -是你你会离开吗
- Why won't they leave? - Would you?
咱不能继续在这待下去了
We can't sit here any longer.
我们从后面出去  跑到车那
Let's head out the back and make a run to the car.
-发生什么了  -有行尸  我搞定它们了
- What happened? - Roamers, I nailed 'em.
他们不见了  但是车还在这
They disappeared but their car's still there.
我找完了那些房子  这栋你们找完没
I cleared those buildings. You guys get this one?
-没呢  -我也没
- No. - Me neither.
咱要找戴夫和托尼
We're looking for Dave and Tony
你俩都没想过去酒吧里找下吗
and no one checks the damn bar?
-怎么了  -有人把门锁了
- What? - Someone pushed it shut.
里面有人
There's someone in there.
里面有人吗
Yo, is someone in there?
如果有人  我们不想惹麻烦
Yo, if someone's in there, we don't want no trouble.
我们只是在找我们的朋友
We're just looking for our friends.
-咱怎么办  -把门撞开
- What do we do? - Bum rush the door?
不  我们不知道里面有多少人  先冷静
No, we don't know how many are there. Just relax.
我们不想惹麻烦
We don't want any trouble.
我们只是在找我们的朋友
We're just looking for our friends.
如果有什么不妥  请告诉我们
If something happened, tell us.
这地方四周都是行尸
This place is crawling with corpses.
如果你们能帮我们逃脱  我们会很感激
If you can help us not get killed, I'd appreciate it.
老兄  你搞错了  这里面没人
Dude, you're bugging. I'm telling you nobody's in there.
有人抓着门把手呢  如果里面有人
Someone guard the door. If they're in there,
他们肯定知道戴夫和托尼在哪
they might know where Dave and Tony are.
他们逼我们的
They drew on us!
戴夫和托尼都在里面吗
Dave and Tony in there?
他们还活着吗
They alive?
-不  -他们杀了戴夫和托尼
- No. - They killed Dave and Tony.
走吧  伙计  咱走吧
Come on, man, let's go.
不  我不走  我才不要告诉简
No, I'm not leaving, I'm not telling Jane.
我才不要回去告诉大伙
I'm not gonna go back and tell them
戴夫和托尼在一个酒吧里被俩混蛋枪杀了
that Dave and Tony got shot by some assholes in a bar.
是你们的朋友逼我们的
Your friends drew on us!
我们没选择的余地
They gave us no choice!
我们都失去过很多人
I'm sure we've all lost enough people,
做过很多迫不得已的事
done things we wish we didn't have to,
现在就是这种情况  你明白的
but it's like that now. You know that!
现在咱就把这个揭过不提
So let's just chalk this up to what it was...
错误的地点
Wrong place,
错误的...
wrong...
离开这  快走
Get outta here! Go!
我们找不到洛莉
We can't find Lori
-其他人也没回来  -对
- and the others aren't back yet either. - Yeah.
那蠢女人肯定是去找他们了
That dumb bitch must've gone off looking for 'em.
-什么  -是的  她让我去
- What? - Yeah, she asked me to go.
我告诉她我不想再当跑腿的了
I told her I was done being an errand boy.
然后你啥也没劝劝她
And you didn't say anything?
别这样
Don't do this.
拜托
Please.
我已经失去了我女儿
I've already lost my girl.
那也用不着我担心
That wasn't my problem neither.
-她不在谷仓里  -我找遍了院子
- She's not at the barn. - I checked the yards.
-那她在哪  -她说过让达里尔去镇上
- Well, where is she? - She asked Daryl to go into town.
她肯定是自己去了
Must've gone herself.
卡尔
Carl.
-你知道这件事吗  -不知道
- Did you know about this? - No.
听着  她带了枪吗
Look, just... Did she take a gun?
我不知道
I don't know.
我才不会让她自己一个人去
I wouldn't let her go out there alone.
我们都清楚这样下去不会有好结果
We all know this is not gonna end well!
对我们大家都没有好处
There's nothing in it for any of us!
你们只要  只要退后
You guys just... Just back off,
就不会再有人受伤
no one else gets hurt!
他娘的
Shit!
格伦  格伦
Glenn! Glenn!
我没事  我没事
I... I'm all right. I'm all right.
洛莉
Lori!
我拖住他们  你去掩护格伦
I'll hold 'em here. You cover Glenn.
看能不能到你车那里
See if you can make it to your car.
告诉他  让他把车停在后面
Tell him... tell him to pull up back.
我们跑过去  然后赶紧离开这
We'll run for it, get the hell out of here.
你想让我去掩护格伦吗
You want me to cover Glenn?
你没参加我们的射击训练
You missed all that gun training.
你要是学过现在就能派上用场了
It could've come in handy now.
我可以射击  我不想做罢了
Nah, I can shoot. I just don't like to.
对不起  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
瑞克要你尽力跑到车那
Rick wants you to try for the car.
尽力
Try?
你尽力就成功了
You'll try and succeed.
我掩护你
I'll cover you.
真是个好计划
That's a great plan.
-怎么了  -他开了枪
- What happened? - He fired.
肯定打中了格伦
He must've hit Glenn.
他在垃圾箱后面
He's behind the dumpster.
好像不动了
Doesn't look like he's moving.
你中枪了吗
You hit?
Are you hit?
没有
No. No.
好了  车就在那边
It's all right. The car's right there.
-好的  -我们就快要回去了
- Okay. - We're almost home.
-没事吧  -没事
- You good? - I'm good.
走吧
Let's go.
回去
Get back.
(史蒂夫大药房)
我们离开这
Let's get out of here!
到处都是行尸  快点
Roamers all over the place! Hurry up!
-我们得离开这  -那西恩呢
- We gotta get out of here! - What about Sean?
他中弹了  我们走  这到处都是行尸
They shot him. We gotta go. Roamers are everywhere.
-我们走吗  -跳下来
- We're leaving? - Jump!
快点  快跳下来
Hurry up, jump already.
-那家伙没跳下来  -救命  帮帮我
- Dude didn't make it. - Help me! Help... help me!
我得走了
I've gotta go. I've gotta go.
-对不起  -不  别走
- I'm sorry! - No no, don't leave!
帮帮我  别走
Help me! No! No!
-去叫赫谢尔  -帮帮我
- Help!- Get Hershel.
救命  帮帮我
Help! Help me!
- 不 不  - 赫谢尔
- No! No!- Her... Hershel!
赫谢尔  赫谢尔
Hershel. Hershel.
肯定是枪声把行尸引来了
The gunfire must've attracted the walkers.
-瑞克呢  -他跑对面去了
- Where's Rick? - He... he ran across.
我们不能丢下他
Well, hell, we can't go without him.
瑞克
Rick!
-我们得走了  -不
- We have to go now.- No!
-闭嘴  -抱歉  我们得走了
- Shh!- I'm sorry, son. We have to go.
-别丢下我  求你了  -我们得走了
- No no, don't leave me please.- We have to go.
-不行  -他刚才还冲我们开枪呢
- We can't.- He was just shooting at us!
-他是个孩子  -求你们帮帮我
- He's a kid.- Please help me.
这地方被行尸包围了
This place is crawling with walkers!
-我们不能丢下他  -栏杆穿透了
- We can't leave him! - The fence went clean through.
我们不可能直接把腿弄出来
There's no way we can get the leg off in one piece.
闭嘴  别出声  要不我打死你
Shut up or I will shoot you!
打死他没准是对的
That may be the answer.
我们得把肌肉扯开
We're not gonna get that leg off
才能把腿弄出来
without tearing the muscle to shreds.
那样他肯定跑不动了  还可能大出血
He certainly can't run.He may bleed out.
闭嘴
Shut up.
对不起  别出声了
I'm sorry.Sh-sh... shut up.
-闭嘴  -也许我们应该打死他
- Shut up.- Maybe we should put him down.
我不想看到更多的杀戮了
I don't wanna see any more killing,
但是把他活着留在这太残忍了
but this is cruel.
我们不能直接把腿弄出来吗
Can't we just take the leg off?
-斧头还在车里吗 -不  不要
- That hatchet still in the car?- No no, don't... don't...
别砍掉我的腿  求你们了
Don't cut my leg off, please.
- 求你们了  别砍我的腿 - 需要砍断骨头吗？
- Please, not my leg.- Will this cut through the bone?
我得切断膝盖骨以下的韧带
I'll have to sever the ligaments below the kneecap,
胫骨上方的切口
cut above the tibia.
他会失去小腿部分
He's going to lose his lower leg.
-不  不要  -我们离开这之后
- No, don't. No.- When we get clear of here,
我们需要去找些火种  烧一下伤口
we're gonna have to find some tinder, cauterize the wound
防止大出血
so he doesn't bleed out.
好吧  没别的选择了  快点
All right, no choice. Hurry up.
天呐  老天
Oh God, oh God.
-不  -把那根棍子递给我
- No!- Hand me that stick.
-给你  -不要
- Here.- No. Ah!
伙计们  有行尸
Guys, walkers.
快点
Hurry up!
闭嘴
Shut up!
老天  到处都是行尸
Oh God.They're everywhere.
赫谢尔  你那怎么样
Hershel, how we doing over there?
我需要搭把手  放轻松
I need more hands!Easy easy.
不要  求你别别别砍掉我的腿
No, don't don't don't cut my leg off please.
快点  我们得走了  我快没子弹了
Come on, we gotta go!I'm almost out of ammo!
我们没时间了  快点  我们走
We don't have much time!Come on, we've gotta go!
拖不住他们了  赫谢尔  快动手
Can't hold 'em off!Hershel, do it now!
-快点  赫谢尔  -没时间了
- Come on, Hershel!- There is no time!
赫谢尔  快点
Hershel, come on!
别丢下我  求你们了  不要
Please don't leave me!Please! No!
别丢下我  求求你们  别丢下我
Please don't leave me!Please! Please don't leave me!
-你没事吧  -我没事
- You all right?- I'm fine.
你有事  我看见车祸现场了
You're not fine.I saw the wreck.
我看看你
Let me look at you. Oh.
怎么回事
What happened?
我低头看地图  结果撞上了一个行尸
Looked down at the map and hit a Walker.
下次别乱走  就不需要看地图了
Next time stay put, you won't need a map.
来  我必须带你回去
Come on, I gotta get you back.
不  我们得找到瑞克
No, we gotta find Rick.
他回来了  他们都回来了
He's back.They're all back.
他们都安然无恙
They're all safe and sound.
-真的吗  -对
- Really? - Yeah.
谢天谢地
Oh thank God.
-你在干什么  -天哪
What are you doing?
照看你
Keeping an eye on you.
真是好心眼啊
Ain't you a peach?
我不会让你离开的
I'm not gonna let you pull away.
你已经有了一席之地
You've earned your place.
要是你把管别人闲事的
If you spent half your time minding
一半时间花在自己女儿身上
your daughter's business instead of sticking your nose
她就不会死了
in everybody else's, she'd still be alive!
接着说
Go ahead.
接着说  然后呢
Go ahead and what?
我是说快走  我不想看到你
I mean just go! I don't want you here!
你真麻烦啊  娘们
You're a real piece of work, lady.
怎么  你要
What, are you gonna make
拿我爹或像我爹的混蛋说事吗
this about my daddy or some crap like that?
你认识杰克
Pfft! Man,you know Jack.
你怕了  你怕了
You're afraid.You're afraid
因为你独自一身  没有老公
'cause you're all alone.You got no husband,
没有闺女
no daughter.
你不知道自己该怎么办
You don't know what to do with yourself.
你不归我管  索菲亚不是我女儿
You ain't my problem!Sophia wasn't mine!
你要做的就是看着她
All you had to do was keep an eye on her!
天哪  你没事吧  发生什么事了
Oh my God, are you all right? What happened?
-出了意外  我没事  -她被袭击了
- I was in an accident. I'm fine, I'm fine.- She was attacked.
是的  瑞克在哪儿
I really am.Where's Rick?
他们还没回来吗
They're not back?
他们在哪里
Where are they?
我得把你先带回来
Look, I had to get you back here.
-你这个混蛋  -洛莉
- You asshole.- Lori.
-他是我丈夫  -我会去找他  会的
- He's my husband.- Lori, I will go after him. I will find him.
凡事有轻重缓急
Hey! Now look, first things first...
我得  我得照顾你
I gotta...I gotta look after you.
我得确保宝宝没事
I gotta make sure the baby's all right, okay?
你要生宝宝了
You're having a baby?
为什么你没告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
来  来确保你没事
Come on. Let's make sure you're all right.
走
Come on.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
I am so sorry
我离开的时候没有告诉你
that I left without telling you.
没关系
It's okay.
我不怕
I wasn't scared.
爸爸什么时候回来
When's dad getting back?
希望很快
Let's hope soon.
你告诉他有宝宝的时候我也要在场
I wanna be there when you tell him about the baby.
亲爱的  他已经知道了
Oh, love, he already knows.
我们只是想找个好时机告诉你
We were just trying to find the right time to tell you.
男孩还是女孩
Is it a boy or a girl?
生出来才知道
Well, we won't know that until it's born.
-我能摸得到到它吗  -得过一阵子
- Will I be able to feel it?- Not for a while.
你肯定有很多问题
You must have a lot of questions, huh?
我们从没谈过心
We never had the talk.
大概是我们忘了
I guess we forgot.
别看我  那是你爸的事
Don't look at me.That's your father's job.
如果是女孩  能叫她索菲亚吗
If the baby's a girl,can we name her Sophia?
伙计
Hey, dude.
是我不对
Hey, I'm sorry, bud.Okay?
-我以为你知道了  -卡尔哥哥
- I thought you knew.- Big brother Carl.
-很酷  对吧  -非常酷
- Pretty cool, huh?- I say that's very cool.
介意我和你妈妈聊会吗
You ...you mind if I talk to your mom a sec?
让她休息会再聊呢
How about a little later after she's had some rest?
洛莉  我必须把你带回来
Lori, I had to get you back here.
否则你不会回来的
You wouldn't have come otherwise.
这样...
How about you...
听我说完如何  拜托
how about you just hear me out, please?
没事的
It's okay.
好吧  给我一点时间
Okay.Give me a minute.
谢谢  伙计
Thanks, bud.
好吧  洛莉  我撒谎了
Okay, Lori, it was a lie.
只是个小谎
It was one little white lie.
但我认为..
But I think that...
我认为你该想想
I think you oughta be thinking about
宝宝平安无事是多么幸运
how lucky we are that your baby's safe.
你没法停止撒谎  对吧
You just can't stop lying, can you?
什么我丈夫平安回来了
My husband is back safe and sound.
什么我丈夫死在医院里了
My husband is dead in some hospital.
你什么时候...
Oh, when are you gonna...when are you gonna
什么时候会停止这么对我
stop throwing that in my face, huh?
我当时以为他...
I thought that he was...
重点是
the point here, Lor,
你不能总这样跑走
is that you cannot keep running off like that.
你当时在想什么
What were you thinking?
我在想我们需要瑞克来保护大家
I was thinking we needed Rick here to keep us safe.
瑞克  是我保护你
Rick? I keep you safe.
像你对奥蒂斯那样吗
Like you did with Otis?
那晚发生了什么事
What happened that night?
从那以后你就变了
You haven't been the same since.
你想知道奥蒂斯发生了什么
You wanna know what happened with Otis?
奥蒂斯的事是因为我爱你
What happened with Otis happened because I love you.
我爱你和卡尔
I love you and I love Carl. That's right.
我和瑞克说了
I told Rick.
什么
What?
你告诉...你告诉他什么了
You told...you told him what?
是不是说你当时以为自己成了寡妇
Did you tell him that you thought you were a widow?
你伤心欲绝  世界末日要到了
That you were grieving and that the world was coming to an end?
说你需要安慰
That that you needed comforting?
你是不是告诉他那是个错误
Did you tell him it was a mistake?
洛莉  那不是真话
You know, Lori, that ain't true.
我们曾拥有的
What we had,
-是真的 -不是
- it was real. - It was not.
-我们做了长久打算  是真的 洛莉 -不是
- It was a long time coming. It was real, Lori.- It was not.
有你  有我
It was you and it was me
还有卡尔  都动了真感情
and Carl, and it was real.
那种感觉很好  不要说不好
It was right.Don't say it wasn't.
不好
It wasn't.
你回忆一下当时的感觉
Just think about what you felt,
一下就可以  你的感觉
just for a second. What you Fe... what you felt.
当时  我们周围的一切都在崩溃
Everything falling apart all around us,
不过
but it...
只有那段时光最美好
it was a one good thing.
这你心里也明白
And you know it's true.
她的情况怎么样
How is she?
脱水
Dehydrated.
我给她输液
I'll set up an I.V.
赫谢尔不在  我也只会这样
Best I can do without Hershel.
嗨
Hey.
你需要些什么
Can I get you anything?
不用  要是我爸在这里就好了
Nah, I just wish my dad was here.
她会没事的
She'll be okay.
为了她  你要坚强些
You just need to be strong for her.
我本来刚要和她说--
I was just reminding her about...
- 算了  不提也罢  - 不
- Never mind. - No no.
我喜欢听
I... I'd love to hear.
我爸要是听到这些  会背过气去
My dad would die if he heard this.
我上大学后第一年暑假回家
My first summer back from college,
开车到家后  丢下行李
I drove home, dumped my stuff off,
直冲到马棚里去骑马
went straight out to the stable for a ride.
我家人刚从教堂回来
My family comes back from church
贝丝在楼上拽过我的东西就开始拆包
and Beth grabs my things and starts unpacking my stuff upstairs.
- 好温馨  -嗯 然后这家伙
- That's sweet. - Yeah, until this one here
开始乱翻我的背包
starts rifling through my backpack.
她发现一个小塑料盒
She finds this little plastic container
里面有些粉色和绿色的糖果
with these pink and green candies inside.
她不知道我一直在服药
She didn't even know I was on the pill.
所以她一想到我和男孩子  还有性  就吓坏了
She was so freaked out by the idea of me, and boys and sex,
她跑到外面把那些药丢到了池塘里
she runs outside and Chucks them in the duck pond.
我骑马过去看到这些后气得大叫
And I ride up, I see this, I'm screaming.
她大哭起来  肖恩跑到外面
She's crying and Shawn runs outside,
以为我们俩人之中有人溺水
thinks one of us is drowning.
等查明事情原委之后
Soon as he figures out what's going on,
那混球大笑一声  掉头就走
the jerk busts out laughing so loud
把我的马弄毛了  结果我们三个满身都是泥巴
that my horse rears up and gets mud all over the three of us.
我爸出来喊道  出了什么事啊
My dad comes out, "what the heck's goin' on out here?!"
她转过头
And she turns around,
眨了眨眼说  爸爸  我们在游泳
bats her eyelids and says,"we're just swimming, daddy."
她的礼拜服上还全是泥巴和鼻涕呢
In her Sunday dress,all covered in snot and mud.
瑞克和格林会救回你的父亲
Rick and Glenn will get your dad back.
格林是好人
Glenn's a good guy.
对
Yeah. He is.
你们真要去冒险吗
Are you sure you wanna risk it?
你可能没法活着回来
You might not make it back.
- 没事的 - 要是肖恩领队
- I'll be fine. - And with Shane at the helm,
我就没法放心  他损失过队友
I wouldn't be too sure.He's lost people before.
他救过我  你想说什么
And he's had my back.What are you insinuating?
他不希望瑞克回来
He doesn't want Rick back,
不希望赫谢尔回来
or Hershel.
他们要是不在  他就可以为所欲为
With them gone,he's got everything he wants
没人敢反抗
and no one to tell him otherwise.
为了这个团队的生存
Shane has done more to keep this group alive
肖恩比任何人做的都多  包括瑞克
than anybody, including Rick.
你不会连这也信吧
You can't possibly believe that.
我信
I do.
兄弟们
Guys.
爸
Dad!
太好了  你没事
You're okay.
帕特里夏  收拾一下库房  准备动手术
Patricia, prepare the shed for surgery.
- 你受伤了吗 - 没有 你这是怎么了
- Are you hurt? - No, but what happened to you?
- 我出车祸了 -车祸 怎么搞的
- I was in a car accident. - Accident? How?
我出去找你
I went looking for you.
她一个人溜了出去  是我带她回来的
Snuck out on her own. Brought her back.
- 你傻了吗  要是--
- Are you crazy? You could've...
- 那边是谁
- Who the hell is that?
兰德尔
That's Randall.
我们没法丢下他不管
We couldn't just leave him behind.
否则他会流血身亡
He would've bled out,
前提是如果他能活那么久的话
if he lived that long.
城里越来越乱
It's gotten bad in town.
我们该拿他怎么办
What do we do with him?
我尽力去修复他的腓肠肌
I repaired his calf muscle as best I can,
不过可能还是有神经损伤
but he'll probably have nerve damage.
他至少一周都站不起来
Won't be on his feet for at least a week.
等能下床后  给他个水壶
When he is, we give him a canteen,
把他带到主干道上  让他自己走吧
take him out to the main road, send him on his way.
这不等于把他送给行尸了吗
Isn't that the same as leaving him for the walkers?
为活下去  他至少可以搏一搏
He'll have a fighting chance.
就让他一走了之吗
Just gonna let him go?
- 他知道我们住处  - 他一路上都是蒙眼过来的
- He knows where we are. - He was blindfolded the whole way here.
- 他不会造成威胁 - 不会吗
- He's not a threat.- Not a threat.
他们原本有多少人
How many of them were there?
你干掉其中三人  拿一人当人质
You killed three of t, zir men,you took one of them hostage,
他们就不会来找人吗
but they just ain't gonna come looking?
他们不管他的死活
They left him for dead.
- 谁都不会找来 - 我们应该派人把守
- No one is looking. - We should still post a guard.
他现在昏迷不醒  还要持续几小时
He's out cold right now, will be for hours.
我去给他拿些鲜花和糖果
You know what? I'm gonna go get him some flowers and candy.
瞧啊  各位  我们又痴人说梦了
Look at this, folks... We back in fantasy land.
在谷仓的事  我们还没说呢
You know, we haven't even dealt with what you did at my barn yet.
让我一次把话说明白
Let me make this perfectly clear, once and for all...
这是我的农场  我本打算让你离开
This is my farm.Now I wanted you gone.
虽说瑞克劝我不要这么做
Rick talked me out of it,
这并不代表我非要听他劝
but that doesn't mean I have to like it.
所以帮你我一个忙  闭上你的嘴
So do us both a favor...Keep your mouth shut.
听着  我们今天先别急着做什么
We're not gonna do anything about it today.
先让大家平静一下
Let's just cool off.
我能和你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you?
你怎么了
What's going on with you?
你父亲今天救了我的命
Your dad saved my life today.
而瑞克又救了我们两个的
And Rick saved us both.
但我...
And I...
呆住了
I froze.
当时有人朝你开枪
Well, you were being shot at.
我知道  但是...
I know, but...
-你不必去证明什么  -我以前做过那么多
- You don't have anything to prove.- All I've done,
但现在却...
then this... okay.
是因为你说的话
It's because of what you said.
那句"我爱你"
That I love you?
没错
Yeah.
一发子弹击中了我身后的墙壁
A bullet hit the wall behind me
然后我想到你...
and I...I thought of you...
失去我  伤心痛苦
Losing me, hurting.
我无法承受  所以我躲起来
And I couldn't take it, so I hid
就为了活命
to stay alive.
-格伦  -别
- Glenn.- No no no.
不  你不明白
No, you don't get it.
瑞克和你父亲  他们依靠我
Rick, your dad...They were counting on me
而我却只想着自己
and I...I only thought of myself.
她吃东西了吗
Has she eaten?
我会给她点镇静剂
I'll give her a sedative...
让她身体不要过度消耗
Stop her body from working too hard.
你跑去喝酒
You were drinking.
现在可不是担心那个的时候
That was the least of my worries.
你丢下我  让我不知所措
You left and I didn't know what to do!
-要我放哨吗  -好的
- Want me to take watch? - Yeah.
换班制  几小时后我去墓地放哨
Relieve T. In a few hours.I'm gonna take the graveyard.
然后呢
And then what?
我们把他开开心心的送走吗
We just send him on his merry way?
瑞克和赫谢尔是这么说的
According to Rick and Hershel.
如果他把他的人引到这里来
If he finds his people and leads them here,
我们之间肯定会开战
we'll have a war on our hands.
你说的我可比你要更清楚
You know you're preaching to the choir, girl.
你有没有想过处事温和点
You ever consider a lighter touch?
放弃搜寻索菲亚
Abandoning the search for Sophia,
杀死谷仓僵尸  今天对洛莉撒谎
taking out the walkers in the barn, lying to Lori today...
你的决定都没错
Those were all the right calls.
是你的表达方式让大家不满
It's your presentation that leaves something to be desired.
戴尔派你来的
Dale send you?
我发现你在疏远所有人
I see you pushing everyone away.
何必呢  他们需要你
For what? They need you.
我永远都是多余的
Huh. I'll always be the odd man out...
-和你一样  -我已经心平气和了
- The same as you. - I've made my peace.
是吗  就我所见
Have you? The way I see it,
你和我  我们遭受了同样的待遇
you and me, we... We're treated the same way.
所有人都想拿走你的枪
Everyone's always trying to take the gun out of your hand.
这些家伙  他们想玩过家家
These folks... They want to play house.
他们想假装瑞克和赫谢尔...
They wanna pretend that Rick and Hershel...
知道自己在做什么  我告诉你
They know what they're doing. Lemme tell you something...
他们一定会害死我们
They bound to get us all killed.
-那我们必须阻止他们  -他们不会听的
- Then we have to stop that. - They don't listen.
他们要给这孩子一个补给包
They're gonna give this kid a care package.
他们要让他回去  你说的对
They're gonna send him on his way. And you right,
这会带来一场大战或更糟的结局
that's gonna bring on a war or something worse,
而我们只能坐着等死
and we just gonna... we're gonna sit here and wait for it.
但你和我
But you and me, we...
我们是唯一预见到危险的人
We're the only ones who see it coming.
早知道我当初就和你一起离开了
I should've left with you when I had the chance.
疼
Oh. Oh man.
我帮你
Here.
谢谢
Thank you. Ah.
帮我一下
Need your help.
来吧
Come here.
我们就像一对老夫老妻
We're like a couple of old people.
我们需要谈谈肖恩
We need to talk about Shane.
他又做了什么
What's he done now?
他认为孩子是他的
He thinks the baby's his.
不管怎样  肯定是你的
No matter what, it's yours.
他会接受的
He'll accept that.
你必须逼他接受  他不听我的
You're gonna have to make him. He won't listen to me.
他胡思乱想还很危险
He's delusional and he's dangerous.
当我去找你的时候  他跟着我
When I went looking for you, he came after me...
-他当然会跟着  -而且他撒谎
- Well, of course he did. - ...And lied to me
为了把我带回来  他说你已经回来了
to get me back here, said you were already back.
你看到他在谷仓的所作所为
You saw what he did at the barn.
他在威胁戴尔和赫谢尔
He's threatened Dale and Hershel.
他吓到大家  他吓到我了
He's scaring people and he's scaring me.
而且我觉得他杀了奥蒂斯
And I think he killed Otis.
我觉得他把奥蒂斯丢下...
I think he left him behind and I think...
不只是为了救卡尔
I think he did it not just to save Carl
-也是因为他爱我...  -你这只是推测
- but because he loves me... - But you don't know that.
他认为我和他才应该在一起
And he thinks that we're supposed to be together
不管发生什么
no matter what.
那些枪手今天丢下了那孩子
Those gunmen left that kid behind today.
而我亲手杀了两个人  为了保护你
I killed two people myself because of you,
卡尔和未出生的孩子
and Carl and the baby.
为了他们我愿意做任何事
It was gonna be me and not them no matter what.
你为了保护自己家人而杀人
You killed the living to protect what's yours?
没错
That's right.
肖恩认为我是他的
Shane thinks I'm his.
他认为孩子是他的
He thinks the baby's his.
他说你没能力保护我们
And he says you can't protect us,
他说你会害死我们
that you're gonna get us killed.
他很危险  瑞克  而且他不会停下
He's dangerous, Rick, and he won't stop.